LOGAN DARRIEL COLLINS

Senior Backend Developer

+1 (516) 654-4426 • hermes8527@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/logan-collins-0a4b31330/ • Lyons, GA, US

Experience

Brewlabs - https://brewlabs.info/

Senior Full Stack Blockchain Developer

04/2023 - 09/2024

Brewlabs is a Binance Smart Chain utility project responsible for a number of community tools and platforms within the cryptocurrency space

- · Hosted and configured CI/CD Pipelines for the landing page with AWS EC2, CodeBuild and CodeDeploy in company landing page
- · Implemented the backend in Node.js to fetch proper data from MongoDB and update database according to the user actions
- · Developed a bot in Node.js to fetch all cryptocurrency assets, price history, and market capacity
- Deployed the bot on AWS EC2 instance and set it up to save data in AWS DynamoDB
- Collaborated with company executives to improve the UI and platform functions and guided users to use the platform in the precise and the best way in the product community

SparkWorld*

Senior Full Stack Blockchain Developer

04/2022 - 03/2023

- · Collaborated with the CTO to clarify and define the main features of NFT Marketplace and Aggregator
- · Made detailed documentation of the system design and workflow of these projects
- Led the backend team to develop high-performance and scalable backend in Golang
- · Collaborated with Smart Contract team to integrate Web3 with Ethers.js library in the frontend using functions from the Smart Contracts
- · Took part as a key member and resolved the conflicts between dev teams in the daily stand-ups and weekly and monthly meetings
- · Developed a bot in Golang to fetch NFT Sale data from NFT Marketplaces to show them on the NFT Aggregator Feed and Sales Page

Satang Technology — https://satang.com/

Senior Full Stack Blockchain Developer

04/2020 - 03/2022

Satang Technology is a tech company focusing on blockchain technology and cryptocurrencies providing full loop consulting and development

- · Implemented RESTful APIs to provide data to show on landing page in Node.js and provided Swagger documentation
- Hosted and configured CI/CD pipelines for the company landing page on AWS
- · Configured Google Firebase for the database to store real estate data and Firestore to save asset files in Asset Tokenizer project
- Developed backend in Node.js to interact between frontend and Google Firebase and Firestore and retrieve user and asset data
- · Collaborated with Smart Contract team to integrate Web3 to consume functions from Smart Contracts for tokens and Marketplace
- Deployed backend on the GCP platform

Polisport – https://polisport.com/, https://polisportvirtualtour.com/

Senior Full Stack Developer

04/2019 - 03/2020

Polisport Group is a company developing and manufacturing Motorcycle & Bicycle Parts & Accessories

- Developed RESTful APIs in microservices architecture in Node.js to retrieve products like motorcycle and bicycle accessories and services data from MongoDB
- Provided Swagger documentation for the RESTful API endpoints and functions
- · Created reusable components and composed them to implement pixel-perfect frontend according to Figma design in React
- Used Redux for global state management in frontend
- · Wrote unit test scripts for every components in frontend and backend using libraries like Jest, Sinon, Mocha, and Chai
- Led Polisport Virtual Tour Project to implement the main UI in React and used the Three.js library for virtual tour in the 3D virtual environment
- Utilized AWS services like EC2 for hosting, DynamoDB for database, and CodePipeline to configure CI/CD pipeline

Canary Technologies — https://glassbororentals.com/, https://ventano.de/, https://hoteline.travel Full Stack Developer 06/2016 - 03/2019

- During six-month internship as a developer, I gained valuable insights into company culture and development methodologies working in an Agile Environment using tools like JIRA for project management, Git for version control, and Web technologies like Laravel, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Created smooth and visually appealing user interfaces as a Frontend Developer in Laravel Blade, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript in Glassboro Rentals project
- Designed MySQL database and contributed to three pages in Laravel as a Full Stack Developer in an ECommerce project called Ventano
- Took part in as a key member in Hoteline project which is a hotel management platform

Summary

Logan Collins is a passionate and self-motivated Senior Backend Developer specializing in Node.js and Golang
He enjoys architecting, designing, planning, and implementing projects from scratch worked in various sizes of companies from start-ups to enterprises

Education

Illinois Institute of Technology Bachelor of Computer Science Chicago, IL 2012 - 2016

Skills

Backend: Node.js · Express.js · Golang · Laravel

Languages: JavaScript · TypeScript · PHP

Databases: MongoDB · MySQL · PostgreSQL

3rd Party Services: Stripe \cdot OAuth2 \cdot Mailgun \cdot Twilio \cdot SendGrid

Communication: RESTful APIs · WebSocket · GraphQL · RPC

Version Control Systems: Git • GitHub • GitLab • Bitbucket

 $\mathsf{DevOps} \colon \mathsf{AWS} \cdot \mathsf{GCP} \cdot \mathsf{Docker} \cdot \mathsf{Kubernetes}$

Methodologies: Scrum · Agile